我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, i'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
But secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present.
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
And now our world is more dangerous than ever,
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
能像那样在室内控制天气
To be able to control the weather like that indoors.
他得是个天气巫师
He'd have to be a weather wizard.
这位是歇洛克
This is Sherloque.
他是多元宇宙中最棒的侦探
He's the greatest detective in all the multiverse.
我是来帮你们抓凶手的
I'm here to catch your killer.
卫星只有一个部位
The only part of the satellite
有这么高浓度的暗物质
that would have dark matter levels that high--
是核心  蝉的匕首就从这里来的
Is the core, which is where Cicada's dagger came from.
我们从联邦应急管理署得到了一份
We got a list from FEMA of everyone
大悟之道那晚上报受伤的名单
who reported injuries the night of the Enlightenment.
其中两个是双胞胎  他们的爸爸去世了
Two of them are twins whose father is deceased,
还有一个是个十岁的女孩
third is a ten-year-old girl
叫格蕾丝·吉本斯
by the name of Grace Gibbons.
如果如我爸所料蝉是个父亲的话  那么
So if my dad's right and Cicada's a father, then...
我们可能找到了他女儿
We may have just found his daughter.
打扰一下
Excuse me,
请问格蕾丝·吉本斯的房间在哪里
could you tell me where Grace Gibbons' room is?
等一下  让我查一下
One sec, let me check.
实际上  她就在右边的第一个房间
Actually, yeah, she's that first room right on the right.
很好
Great.
你这是要去哪
Just where do you think you're going?
我觉得你好像是要进我病人的房间
Into my patient's room is what I looks like.
我很抱歉  我是巴里·艾伦
I'm sorry. I am Barry Allen.
我是中城警局的
I'm with the CCPD.
我本来也想找你谈话的  实际上
I was hoping to speak with you, actually.
我在找格蕾丝·吉本斯的父母
I'm looking for Grace Gibbons' parents.
尤其是她的父亲
Specifically her father.
我很抱歉  可是她的父母都已过世了
I'm sorry, but the girl's parents are deceased.
你确定吗
Are you sure about that?
我可以给你看她的病历
I can show you her charts.
你自己看看
See for yourself.
她入院时  医院刚好有大量的新收病人
She came in with a wave of new admissions.
没有合法的监护人  没有近亲
No legal guardian listed, no next of kin.
令人悲伤的事实是
The sad truth is,
我们医院员工是这个小女孩最后的亲人
our staff is the only family this little girl has left.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢你的帮助
Thank you for your help.
奥林·德怀尔  你在里面吗
Orlin Dwyer, are you in there?
是中城警局  打开门
It's CCPD. Open up.
奥林·德怀尔
Orlin Dwyer?
听着  伙计
Hey, listen, man,
我不在乎那个人是怎么说的
I don't care what that guy says,
他喝醉了  然后我只是在自卫
he was drunk and I was defending--
这是关于你姐姐的消息  德怀尔先生
This is about your sister, Mr. Dwyer.
她出意外了  是超能力者袭击事件
There's been an accident, a meta attack.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第七集
小心点
Careful.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
现在是关键时刻
This is a critical time.
好的
Okay.
双手保持稳定
Steady hands.
嗯
Yeah.
宣布"死亡时间"
Call time of death.
没关系  这是馅饼
It's okay. It's a pie.
本来就不应该是小菜一碟
It's not supposed to be a piece of cake.
多谢你帮助我
Hey, thanks for helping.
虽然追踪蝉的线索中断了
With Cicada's trail running cold,
但至少我们有多一天可以去准备
at least we have the extra day to prepare
在小阁楼的第一个感恩节
for our first Thanksgiving at the loft.
乔和塞西尔呢
What about Joe and Cecile?
他们今年和塞西尔的家人一起庆祝
They're celebrating with Cecile's family this year.
所以  今年就只有我们五个人
So, yeah, this year it's just gonna be the five of us.
我很乐意
I'm down.
六个  实际上
Six, actually.
冰霜杀手刚刚也回复了
Killer Frost just RSVP'd.
什么  你们俩现在可以互相交谈
What--you guys can just talk to each other now,
即使没有内心活动缓冲器
even without the mental activity dampener?
是的  其实今天是第一次这样
Yeah, today's actually the first time.
天哪
Oh, gosh.
-嗨  你们好  -嗨
- Hi, guys. - Yo.
抱歉我们迟到了
Sorry we're late.
仿佛所有人都和他们的奶奶
It seems like everyone and their grandma is getting
在节日前做美甲
pre-holiday manis and pedis.
我们来拍照片然后发布在
Ooh, let's take photos and post them
你们现在用的老式"照片墙"社交软件
on that old-fashioned Insta thingy that you guys use.
她们俩好像真的冰释前嫌了
Those two seemed to have really patched things up.
是的  诺拉现在跟爱瑞丝比我还要亲近
Yeah, Nora's getting closer to Iris than she is with me,
而且现在的时机再好不过了
and the timing couldn't have been better.
什么意思
What do you mean?
我是说  我在未来消失的时候
I mean, Nora was so young
诺拉还那么小
when I disappeared in her future,
所以这应该是她记忆里的第一次
so this would be her first memory of Thanksgiving
和爸爸妈妈一起过的感恩节
with both her parents.
我感觉准备一个最完美的感恩节
Feel like it's my job to make it
是我的工作
the most perfect Thanksgiving ever.
标签写"手模特"
And #HandModels.
我觉得自己是个红人了
Wow, I feel famous already.
天哪
Oh, man.
妈妈
Mom, um...
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起什么  诺拉
Sorry for what, Nora?
没给你机会向我表现你的好
For not giving you a chance to show me how great you are.
今年我真的很感激有机会能了解你
This year I'm just really thankful to get to know you.
真正的你
The real you.
我也很感激
I'm thankful too.
韦斯特艾伦家每年都要过感恩节
You know, the West-Allens have never missed a Thanksgiving.
就算是大猩猩军队   邪恶极速者
No gorilla army, no evil speedster,
天大的虫洞都无法阻止我们
no giant wormhole in the sky could break that streak.
没错  奇点
Yeah, the singularity.
闪电侠博物馆有老爸的3D模型
So the Flash Museum has a 3-D model of Dad
是他冲进去拯救城市的样子
just running straight into it to save the city.
天哪  那场面肯定很壮观
God, it must have been so epic to be there.
其实
Actually, it was...
那场面很吓人
terrifying to be there.
我们不知道你爸是否会回来
We didn't know if your dad was gonna come back.
罗尼就没回来
Ronnie didn't.
什么
What?
博物馆说老爸救了所有的人
The museum says that-- that Dad just saved everybody.
我猜有些事博物馆没有公开
I guess there's things the museum left out.
比如你爸为了拯救城市
Like your Dad giving himself to the Speed Force
献身于神速力
to save the city.
还有一次我们在道别时想着
That was another time we said good-bye thinking...
这次也许有去无回了
might be a one-way trip.
听起来和他在未来离开我们的原因很相似
Sounds a lot like what took him from us in the future.
我都不知道老爸经历过这么多次死里逃生
I didn't know Dad had so many close calls.
你爸总以救人为先
Look, your dad is always gonna
牺牲自己也在所不惜
wanna put his life on the line for others.
这就是我最爱他的地方
That is what I love most about him,
但是这却让我晚上无法安睡
but, yeah, it-- it does keep me up at night.
他有回来吗
Did he come back?
没  我伪造的记录暂时让他信服了
No, the records I falsified convinced him for now.
所以我们安全了
So we're safe?
奥林  我觉得你还是别来了
Orlin, I think you need to stay away.
好主意
Good idea.
周末之后我再去医院
I won't visit till after the weekend.
不  我觉得你应该别再来了
No, I think you need to stay away for good.
越来越冒险了
It's getting too risky.
你要我抛弃格蕾丝吗
You want me to give up Grace?
不行  不行
No, no, no, listen,
你不能把我晾在一边
you can't put me on hold.
我不在乎近亲什么的废话
I don't care about this next of kin crap.
我不想这个孩子  喂
I don't want this kid. Hello?
喂
Hello?
该死的
Damn it.
什么事
What?
该吃早餐了
It's breakfast.
是的  没错
Yeah, it is. Um...
好
Okay.
这个只放了几天而已
Now look, it's only a few days old.
我保证还是很好吃的
It's still good, I swear.
我不明白
I don't understand.
再给我解释一下
Explain again to me
在美国今天这个日子
what the difference between this day
和平常的日子有区别吗
and every other day in America?
这是一个我们团聚一堂
It's a holiday when we all get together
一起庆祝  大吃大喝的节日
and celebrate and eat a ton of food.
很多很多吃的
Like, a gross amount.
还是那句话  在美国今天这个日子
Again, what the difference between this day
和平常的日子有区别吗
and every other day in America.
-这是法定的  -两位好
- That's legit. - Hi, guys.
怎么了
What's going on?
这家伙想要给我解释感恩节是什么
This guy, he try to explain the Thanksgiving holiday.
但是他根本没解释出来  这到底是什么节
He's failing miserably. What is this holiday?
-请解释一下  -其实很简单
- Please explain. - It's very simple, actually.
就是大家团聚一堂
It's just about getting together
庆祝我们的爱人与家人
to celebrate our loved ones and family.
这么简单  所以我才不明白这个节日
So simple, this is why I don't understand this holiday.
我没有家人
I don't have any family.
你不是结过七次婚吗
Didn't you have, like, seven marriages?
我的确结过七次婚
I did have seven marriages.
五位太太  七次婚姻  但却没有家人
Five wives, seven marriages, but no family.
这个节日太伤人了
This holiday is a cruel holiday.
出什么事了
What's going on?
市中心的发电站
I'm seeing a massive electrical surge
有一股巨大的电涌
at the downtown power station.
巴里  诺拉  行动
Barry, Nora, you're up.
各位  问题在哪
Guys, what's the problem?
一切好像...
Everything looks--
我们找到原因了
I think we found it.
-是闪电  -天空前一刻还万里无云
- It's lightning. - Skies were clear a minute ago.
风暴肯定是凭空出现的
That storm must have come out of nowhere.
这下我们有更大的麻烦了
Uh, we got a bigger problem.
水星实验室在那个发电站里
There's an experimental cold fusion core
有一个实验冷聚变反应堆芯  如果爆炸的话
from Mercury Labs in the plant, and if it blows...
堆芯可能会炸毁整个街区
It could take out the whole block.
我看到了
I see it.
诺拉  把所有工作人员疏散到安全地带
Nora, you've got to evac all the workers to safety.
-巴里  -我知道  我要去拿堆芯
- Barry-- - Yeah, I know, I got to grab the core.
不不不  感觉不对劲
No, no, no, something doesn't feel right.
照爱瑞丝说的做  把工作人员带出来
Just listen to Iris. Grab the workers from inside.
爸
Dad!
他没有呼吸了
You guys, he's not breathing.
他要心跳停止了
He's going into cardiac arrest.
她必须复苏他的心脏
She needs to restart his heart.
什么  我该怎么做
What-- how do I do that?
双手摩擦  制造闪电
Rub your hands together to create lightning,
然后给他个胸外按压
and then give him a chest compression.
好  好
Okay! Okay.
快啊  快啊
Come on. Come on. Come on.
不起作用啊
It's not working!
我们失去他了
We lost him.
不  不
No! No!
不
No!
求你了  求你了
Please. Please. Please.
他活过来了
He's back.
-我向你保证  我没事  -凯特琳
- I promise I'm okay. - Caitlin.
他的体征信号稳定  极速治愈救了他
His vitals are stable. Speed healing to the rescue.
他不应该需要解救的
He shouldn't have needed rescuing.
诺拉  我知道你很沮丧
Nora, I know you're upset,
但是那个堆芯可能会爆炸
but if that core would have exploded
导致造成很大的伤害
it would have caused a lot of damage.
它已经造成大伤害了  爸爸死了
It did cause a lot of damage. Dad died.
我们根据当时情况做出了最好的决定
We made the best decision we could, given the circumstances.
也许需要换个人来做我们的决定
Maybe someone else should be making our decisions.
那好吧
Wow, all right, well,
看来母女假期时光结束了
so much for mother-daughter holiday time.
她刚才确实把我救活了
She did just have to bring me back to life.
-咱们给她点时间  -好吧
- Let's give her a minute. - Okay.
与此同时  那风暴是哪里来的
In the meantime, where did that storm come from?
这样一个来去自如的风暴
A storm like that coming and going,
一分钟之内就消失了
disappearing in a matter of minutes,
应该是不可能的
it shouldn't be possible.
除非是有人操纵的
Unless someone was making it possible.
我是说  我之前见识过
I mean, we've seen that before.
-天气巫师  -但是马克·马登在
- Weather Wizard. - But Mark Mardon is serving
铁山监狱服无期徒刑呢
a life sentence at Iron Heights.
咱们先确认下他还在服刑呢吧
Let's make sure he's doing just that.
如果还有其他天气异常
Let us know if any other weather anomalies
出现在雷达上就通知我们
pop up on the radar.
好的
Okay.
没问题
Will do.
我想是时候进行"拯救火鸡行动"了
I think it's time for operation: Save the Turkey.
什么...
What...?
艺术就是疗法
Art is therapy.
那么  夏洛克
So, Sherlock--
歇洛克  很简单的读音
Sherloque, simple pronunciation.
我们听到你说的关于没有家人的事了
We heard what you had to say about not having a family.
好  我们闪电小队这里
Right. And we here at Team Flash are
都像是一家人  你也成为了家人
sort of a family, and you're becoming part of that family,
所以我们想请你一起
so we would like to invite you
来庆祝感恩节
to celebrate Thanksgiving with us.
凯特琳  我恐怕得拒绝了  好吗
Caitlin, I'm afraid that I must decline, all right?
因为我没有什么庆祝的原因
Because I don't have a lot of reason to celebrate,
我觉得你更应该能够理解
and you of all people should sympathize with that.
-我为什么能理解  -你失去了父亲  对吗
- Why should I sympathize? - You lost your father, right?
你找回他之后却发现他的身体
And then you find him only to discover that his body
被一个冰柱恶魔附身
is being possessed by a icicle demon
还想要杀死闪电小队
who's trying to kill all of Team Flash,
也包括你自己  不是很棒  对吗
yourself included. Not great, right?
好吧  够了  负能量狂魔
Okay, that's enough, Debbie Downer.
别听他的  你知道吗
Don't listen. You know what?
也许你确实缓一缓你那怒气
Maybe you should lay off the paint fumes.
你知道吗  小拉尔夫·马奇奥
Do you know what, young Ralph Macchio?
你也没什么值得庆祝的
You have nothing to celebrate either, right?
你这一年都是什么情况
What your last year has been, huh?
我给你回顾下  首先是分手
Let me recap for you. First, heartbreak.
然后是蝉碾碎了你的超能力
And then second, Cicada crushes your powers
迫使你假装死亡
forcing you to fake your own death,
也不是很好  而至于我
also not great, and as for me,
多次离婚让我
multiple divorces have left me
背上负债的重负喘不过气
with a mountain of debt that's insurmountable.
过去这一年对我们来说都不是很好
So this past year, not been very kind to any of us.
借过
Pardon.
开放探望时间
她过去有过几次爆发
She's had a few recent outbursts,
而且我们这里也不允许说脏话
and we don't allow cursing here.
这种行为不能再继续了
This type of behavior cannot continue.
总之  就是这些事情
Anyway, that's the long and short of it.
我给你俩一点时间
I'll give you two a moment.
你叫那孩子王八羔子
You called a kid a rat bastard?
你是怎么回事  你不知道
What's wrong with you? Don't you know
不能对别人说这种话吗
you can't go around saying stuff like that?
为什么
Why?
因为之后我会接到电话
Well, 'cause then I get a phone call.
你知道吗  我得请假才能来这里
You know, I had to take off work to come down here.
-反正你也不喜欢你那工作  -什么
- You don't even like your job. - What?
你整天坐在沙发上
You stay on the couch all day,
然后工作电话一来
and then when work calls
你就骂一句然后砸门离开
you curse and slam the door.
"王八羔子"
"Rat bastards."
我知道你是从哪学的了
Look, I get where you heard it.
但是你不能说这种话
All right, but you can't say those words.
-王八羔子  -别闹了
- Rat bastard! - Hey, quit it.
-王八羔子  -住口
- Rat bastard! - Stop.
-王八羔子  -听话
- Rat bastards! - Hey, listen to me!
我可是家长
I'm supposed to be the parent here.
不 你不是家长
No, you're not a parent!
家长应该让孩子过得更开心
Parents are supposed to make the world better for their kids.
你让一切都变糟了  我讨厌你
You make everything worse. I hate you,
你都讨厌你自己
and you hate you too.
抱歉这里灯光很暗
You have to excuse our dim lighting.
今天在电厂的那个风暴
Today's storm out at the power plant
破坏了我们的主发电机
knocked out our main generator,
所以现在靠的是备用发电机
So we're working off a backup for the time being.
那就是说你没法抑制
So does that mean you can't dampen
犯人的超能力了
the meta prisoner's powers?
监狱范围内的超能力阻尼器没用
Prison-wide dampeners are down,
但以防意外我们给每位犯人戴上了超能力手铐
but we got every inmate into meta cuffs incident free.
希望你在报道里把我们这预备措施也写上
I hope you include that in your article about our readiness.
上任监狱长腐败事件后
After the corruption of the last warden,
我正迫切地想向公众证明
I am eager to assure the public
他们的安全不会受到威胁
that their safety is in good hands.
那么各位鉴证员  你们要见哪个犯人
Now, our CSIs, which inmate did you need to see?
他整天都在这里吗
And he's been here all day?
从没离开过我们的视线
Never once out of our sight.
今天有一起犯罪
There was a crime committed today
作案风格很像马登
with an MO similar to Mardon's.
我能看一下监控录像吗
Can I take a look at the security tapes?
乐意为我们的媒体朋友效劳
Anything for our friends in the press.
看来是白跑了
Well, this is a bust.
看样子你白死了一回
Yeah, looks like you died for nothing.
诺拉  听着
Nora, hey, hey, look.
我知道今天你不好过
This has been a rough day for you,
但是你不能把事情怪在爱瑞丝头上
but you can't blame Iris for what happened.
她尽力了
She's doing the best she can.
而且这个计划是我们共同决定的
Besides, we both decided on the plan.
我知道
Oh, I know.
怎么回事...
What the...?
别介意
Hey, don't mind me.
我只是来接我爸爸
I'm just here to pick up my dad.
她说"爸爸"吗
Did she say "Dad"?
乔斯琳
Joslyn?
是乔斯
It's Joss.
带我爸爸来  马上
Bring me my father! Now!
你想得美
Yeah, that's not gonna happen.
那等着瞧吧
We'll see about that.
一小时内把我爸爸带去波特广场
Bring my dad to Porter Plaza in one hour,
不然中城就要遭殃了
or Central City is gonna get wrecked.
我不知道乔斯琳要帮我越狱
I didn't know that Joslyn was busting me out.
她做的那些事我都不敢想象
I didn't know she'd do half the things she does.
我很多年没和她说话了
I haven't spoken to her in years.
你要我相信她今早起床
And you expect me to believe she woke up
然后突发奇想  "你猜怎么着
this morning and was like, "You know what?
我要把我爸爸从铁山公寓里劫出来"
I wanna break my dad out of Iron Heights."
我明白  但这是事实
I get it, but it's the truth.
乔斯出生的时候我和她妈妈还在上高中
Joss was born when me and her mom were still in high school.
而我没法跟那女人相处下去
I never could work out how to be with that woman.
乔斯出生后  我觉得最好的办法
Then when Joss came I thought the best thing to do
就是专注我的事业
was to focus on my career.
你的犯罪事业
Your criminal career?
所以我把她交给她妈妈养了
That's why I left her with her mom.
直到她们发生争吵  她离家出走了
Least until she ran away because some of falling out.
乔斯和她妈妈怎么了
What happened with Joss and her mom?
我最后一次和她谈话
The last time I spoke to her
她跟我说  她和乔斯关系破裂了
she told me that her and Joss are broken.
你懂的
You know how it is.
有时候母女关系破裂了
Sometimes mothers and daughters break
就没办法补救了
and there ain't no fixing 'em.
好  小心脚下
Okay, watch your step.
睁开眼睛
And open your eyes.
这是谁的房子
Whose house is this?
我表哥罗比的
It's my cousin Robbie's.
他现在不住在这里了  但他说
He doesn't live here anymore, but he said
如果我能把这里修整好  我们就可以住
if I fix it up, we could stay here.
这是什么
What's this?
这是个玩偶屋
That is a dollhouse.
等我们布置好了
Or it can be
它就变成玩偶屋了  你可以...
once we build it, and, you know, you can...
挑一些家具  挑颜色
Pick out furniture, and colors,
挑壁纸  任你装饰
or wall paper, decorate it how you want.
我知道  过去的几个月
I know we didn't get off to the greatest start
算不上最好的开头
these past few months.
好吧
Okay...
是很差劲的开头
it was a lousy start.
但我想要弥补这一切
But I want to fix all that.
我想  在我修整这房子的时候
Well, I was thinking that while I work on this place,
我们也可以一起修整这间小房子
we could work on this one too... together.
听着  你说的对  孩子
Listen, you were right, kid.
我的确讨厌自己
I do hate me.
我不知道我还能变成什么样
I don't really know any other way to be,
但我想好好养育你  格蕾西
but I want to do right by you, Gracie.
我想保证你的安全和温饱
I want to keep you safe, and warm, fed...
就是想...
You know, just...
给你一个孩子应有的一切
give you all the things a kid should have.
我们开始装扮玩偶屋吧
Let's start with the dollhouse.
好
Okay.
爸爸的审问怎么样了
How's Dad's interrogation going?
一会儿就知道了  希望他能找到
Well, we'll know in a minute. Hopefully, he'll find something
确认马登女儿身份的线索
that'll help us profile Mardon's daughter.
找到后告诉我
Okay, well, let me know.
诺拉  听着  我知道你生我的气
Nora, look, listen, I know you're upset with me
因为我之前让你爸爸处于危险中
for sending your dad into that situation earlier,
我只是...
and I just--
-我只是想说  -妈妈  没事
- I wanted to say that I-- - Mom, it's okay.
我没生你的气
I'm not upset with you.
-没有吗  -没有  我们之间没事
- You're not? - No, we're good.
我保证
I-I promise.
那就好
Okay, cool.
还有  庆祝对土著文化的毁灭
That's the other thing, celebrating the decimation of an indigenous culture
就为了让那些贪婪的殖民者吃上火鸡
so a bunch of greedy colonizers can get their turkey-lurkey on.
你知道这事吗  这个骗局
Do you know about this? Do you know about the sham?
这个我们称为"感恩节"的骗局
The sham we call "Thanksgiving."
等等  出什么事了
Okay, I'm sorry, am I missing something?
你们什么时候开始抵制感恩节了
Since when did you guys become anti-Thanksgiving?
因为一群戴着搭扣帽的家伙
Since a bunch of guys wearing hat-buckles
灌输给我们过时的鬼话
fed us some old bull, wrapped in lies,
充斥着谎言和阴谋
stuffed in propaganda.
简直就是"火鸡鸭"版骗局
It's a deception Turducken.
香肠熏肉塞进鸡内  再塞进鸭子
再塞进火鸡制成的食品
实际上  我认为搭扣帽也是假的
Actually, I think the hat-buckles weren't real either.
你别怂恿他了
Don't encourage him.
你懂的
You get it.
马登那边有线索吗
Did you get anything from Mardon?
没有能帮助我们找到他女儿的线索
No, nothing that'll help us find his daughter.
你们呢  查到了什么
What about you guys? What'd you dig up?
乔斯·贾科姆
Meet Joss Jackam.
一个青少年惯犯变成了业余风暴追逐者
She is a delinquent teen turned amateur stormchaser.
一个自学成才的理论气象学专家
A self-taught expert in theoretical meteorology.
怎么知道她是风暴追逐者的
How do we know she's a storm chaser?
因为这个海伦·亨特有个博客
'Cause Helen Hunt here has a blog.
因为她做了太多危险的气象实验
Mm-hmm. She lost her grant from the Science Center
而失去了科研中心的实验经费
for doing too many dangerous experiments on the weather.
看起来她做的远远超出了实验的范畴
Well, look like she's way beyond the experimental phase.
天气女巫
Ooh, Weather Witch?
听起来不赖
I'll allow it.
爸爸  那个风向标
Dad, that weathervane,
看起来非常像
doesn't it look a lot like...
她手里拿的棍子
The staff she was carrying, yeah.
西斯科  把她攻击铁山监狱时的
Cisco, can you pull up the security footage
监控录像调出来
from her attack on Iron Heights?
好的
Sure can.
安全监控
棍子上嵌入了卫星碎片
It's infected with a satellite shard.
她用了超能科技
She's got meta-tech.
就好像斯宾塞·扬的手机那样
Like Spencer Young's phone.
她能在瞬间召唤闪电
Look, she has instant lightning on command.
你们不可能从她那里夺走这根棍子
There's no way you're gonna be able to get that staff from her.
只能让她自愿交出来了
She's gonna have to give it up willingly.
在她毁掉整个城市之前
Okay, listen, we got 20 minutes
我们还有二十分钟
before she destroys the entire city,
那计划是什么
so what is the plan?
我们只有一个选择
We only have one choice.
满足她的需求
We give her what she wants.
没发现天气女巫
No Weather Witch in sight.
辛格清查了周边
Okay, Singh cleared the perimeter,
周围没有平民
so it's free of civilians.
我们的卫星也在盯着天气变化
And our satellites are on weather watch
来追踪天气女巫  还没有发现
for our Weather Witch. Nothing yet.
什么
What?
不是完全没有发现
I wouldn't say nothing.
我的数据显示
My data leaves me to conclude
有来源未知的人为造成的
that there is artificially-created
大气压强体系
pressure system of uncertain origin
急速扩散朝着市中心的核心去了
headed rapidement toward the downtown core.
听着  伽利略  你想舔舔手指
Listen, Galileo, you can lick your finger
然后测试风向  随你便
and stick it in the wind all you want.
但请你把实际的计算
Why don't you leave the actual calculations
留给实际的电脑  我的天啊
to actual compu-- oh, for Christ's sake.
极端天气逼近
你的恼怒也让我知道了
And your exasperation leads me also to conclude
你终于后知后觉意识到了
that you have realized, although late,
我又一次说对了  我说对了  我说对了
that once again I'm right. I'm right. I'm right.
我说对了  我说对了
I'm right. I'm right--
受够你了
That's enough out of you.
她来了
She's here.
有其父必有其女
So the rotten apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
原来你是个诗人  真棒
You're a poet. Awesome.
我爸爸在哪里
Where's my dad?
乔斯  我们信守承诺
All right, Joss, we held up our end of the bargain.
我们把你爸爸交给你
You got dad.
没必要再伤害其他人
There's no reason to hurt anybody--
真是废话连篇
Ah, so boring. Come on.
剩下的我们来解决
We'll handle it from here.
宝贝女儿
Hey, baby girl.
爸爸
Dad.
这棍子很炫酷
That's a pretty cool staff.
你何不先把它关掉一会
Would you just--how about you just power that thing off for a sec
让你老爸来试试
and let your dad try.
试试这个吧
Try this.
没必要难过  他是个自私的混蛋
Oh, oh, don't feel bad. He was a selfish dick
抛弃了自己的家人
who abandoned his family.
谢谢你们帮我干掉我爸
Anyway, thanks for helping me drop a truck on my dad.
伙计们
Uh...guys?
现在怎么办
What now?
我没预料到那辆悍马砸下来
I didn't see the hummer coming.
气死我了
I'm so pissed!
这座城市将会被淹没
This city will drown,
粉碎  燃烧  都是因为你们
crumble, burn, because of you!
谢谢
Thanks.
我去追她
I'm gonna follow her.
等等  你不是认真的吧
Wait, are you serious right now?
-怎么了  -你差点死了
- What? - You almost just died.
又差点死了  而你好像一点也不在意
Again, and you don't seem to care.
你这是怎么了
Where is this coming from?
你知道我们的工作有多危险
You know how dangerous our job is.
我知道  但我不想再一次失去你
Yeah, but I don't want to lose you again,
但是你看起来一点也不在乎会失去我
but you don't seem to give a damn if you lose me,
你在乎的只有工作
and-- and all for your job.
诺拉
Nora.
你刚才那句话憋了多久了
How long you been holding that one in?
要我说  是一辈子
My best guess? My whole life.
在没有你的情况下长大  我很愤怒
Growing up without you, I was so angry...
但是你是我的英雄  所以
but you were my hero, so...
把因为你不在的愤怒发泄给犯罪和超能力反派
it was easier to put my anger for you not being around
对我来说更容易一些
on criminals and meta-villains...
很多时候还会发泄在妈妈身上
a lot of times on Mom.
但是今天我看到你死去的时候
But when I saw you die today
让我想起
it reminded me that
对于失去你这件事  我在生另一个人的气
I'm mad at someone else about losing you...
是你
You.
我明白
I get it.
有一个为别人冒生命危险的父亲
It's not easy having a parent
对你来说并不容易
who puts their life on the line for others.
我小时候对于乔是一名警察这件事
I remember feeling the same way about Joe
也是这样想的
being a cop when I was a kid.
不  这不一样
No, it's not the same thing.
他曾经在明知不会回来的情况下
Did he ever have to say good-bye to you knowing
和你说再见吗
that he wasn't coming back?
你这样做过
You did...
而且你还会再次这样做
and you're gonna do it again.
诺拉  你要知道你正在谈论的
Nora, you got to remember you're talking about
是我们也许会避免的未来
a future that we might be able to avoid.
我们还有时间找出解决办法
We still have time to find our way to a solution,
而且我们会找到的
and we will.
有一个方法
But there is a solution.
只不过你不想这样做
It's just one that you don't want.
放弃做闪电侠
Give up being The Flash.
这是唯一能够保证
Come on. It's the only way to guarantee
你在未来或者在任何时间
that you won't disappear again in the future,
都不会再一次消失的办法
or any other time.
-诺拉  -拜托  考虑一下
- Nora. - Come on. Think about it.
你不是唯一一个英雄
You're not the only hero.
让其他人去保护世界
Let the others protect the world.
你不需要一直牺牲自己
You don't have to keep sacrificing yourself.
你一次又一次牺牲生命
You give your life again and again.
有多少次是一定要由你来做
How many times does it have to be you?
在我还不了解你的时候就失去你
It hurt so much losing you
都这样痛苦
when I didn't even know you,
但现在经历了这几个月
but now after all of these months
逐渐了解你以后  我只是
getting to know you I just--
求求你  爸爸  别让我再经历一次
please, Dad, don't make me go through it again.
我不想再经历一次了
I don't want to go through it again.
诺拉  人们需要闪电侠
Nora, people need The Flash.
我需要我爸爸
I need my dad.
中城医院
这是今天的第三个冰淇淋了
This is the third ice cream of the day, you know?
你这样做一定有别的原因
Something fishy's going on here.
好吧  被你发现了
Okay, you got me.
我们在庆祝
We're celebrating
因为今天是一个特殊的日子
because this is a very special day.
一年前的今天
One year ago today,
我答应过你
I made you a promise
我会改变我的生活
that I would turn my life around
让你过上更好的生活
and make things better for you.
我可以坦诚地说
I can honestly say that my life
我的生活比过去好了很多
is a million times better than what it was.
这都是因为你  格蕾西
And it's all because of you, Gracie.
所以我给你带了件东西
So I got you something.
这正是我想要的那一套
It's the set I wanted.
我想你的玩偶屋可能需要一个家庭
I thought your little dollhouse could use a family.
我已经有一个了
I already have one.
我爱你  宝贝
I love you, kiddo.
紫色的
Purple.
我想一天吃四个冰淇淋应该会...
You know, I think four ice creams in a day would be the--
格蕾西  快跑
Gracie, run.
快跑  快点
Run. Run. Come on!
这边走  这边走
Go this way! Go this way!
帮帮我
Help me!
快帮帮我
Help me, please!
-先生  -有人吗
- Sir. - Somebody!
求你救救她
Save her, please.
把他送去手术
Get him on a table.
快去
Move!
格蕾西
Gracie...
救救她
Help her...
感恩节前夕
On the eve of Thanksgiving,
关于灾难性天气现象的报道
reports of devastating weather phenomena
在城市各处出现
are streaming in from all over the city.
造成干扰的具体原因尚不明确
The exact cause of these disturbances remains unknown.
我不敢相信她真的会
I can't believe she's actually willing
为了杀死一个人而摧毁整个城市
to level the city to kill one man.
她不知道马登在哪
She doesn't know where Mardon is.
这太过了  但是我们留给她的唯一选择
It's overkill, but it's the only option we've left her.
凯特琳在监测雷达
Well, Caitlin's on radar,
西斯科正在试图给卫星充能
and Cisco's trying to juice the satellites,
但是我们受到了干扰  无法定位到乔斯
but there's interference. We can't locate Joss.
你还好吗
You okay?
亲爱的  你会想出合适的话
Look, babe, you're gonna find the words
让她理解的  我相信你
to make her understand. I know it.
我都不确定能让自己理解
Not sure I have the words to make myself understand.
她说得有道理
She's got a point.
我们找到乔斯了
We got a hit on Joss.
她在谢尔登县机场
She's at Sheldon County Airport.
乔斯·贾科姆
巴里  你要行动了
Barry, you got to move.
你还好吗
You're good?
巴里  你看到乔斯了吗
Barry, do you have eyes on Joss?
没有  她严重损坏了航站楼
No, she's damaged the terminal so badly
机库是唯一安全的地方
the hangar's the only safe place.
我正在疏散被困在停机坪上的人
I'm evacuating everyone trapped on the tarmac.
我可以把冰霜杀手放出来  我们能做什么
I think I can bring Frost out. What can we do?
防洪
Flood control
去马里纳
down at the Marina.
各位  我们该怎么对抗天气
Guys, how do we fight weather?
我们用天气来对抗天气
We fight weather with weather.
诺拉
Nora.
我们还有马登的天气魔棒
We still have Mardon's weather wand.
我需要你去档案馆取出来
I need you to get it from the archives
然后带给巴里  好吗
and take it to Barry, okay?
好的
Okay.
-你好  -你好
- Hey. - Hey.
马登的魔棒
Mardon's wand?
西斯科说你可以用它来抵消乔斯的天气
Cisco says you can use it to counteract Joss's weather.
她在哪里
Where is she?
最后一次机会  我爸爸在哪里
Last chance. Where's my Dad?
乔斯  你知道我们不能把他交出来
Joss, you know we can't give him up.
那你们会知道接下来将发生什么
Then you know what happens next.
乔斯  是我骗了你好吗  不是他们
Joss, I deceived you, okay? Not them.
你想让人付出代价  这个人是我
You want make someone pay, it's me.
你就是这样让英雄付出代价
This is how you make heroes pay!
宙斯的胡子啊
By the beard of Zeus,
她正从闪电中制造龙卷风
she's making a tornado out of lightning.
西斯科  我要怎么用魔棒来阻止它
Cisco, how do I use this wand to stop this?
你可以把所有的闪电都引到魔棒上
You can attract all the lightning to the wand.
这会消除龙卷风
That'll take down the tornado,
但所有的能量都会穿过你的身体
but all that energy will go through your body.
你会成为一根人形避雷针
You'll be a human lightning rod.
没事的
It's okay.
我知道你得去做
I know you have to go.
快跑  爸爸
Run, Dad.
快跑
Run!
往后靠  大家往后靠
Back. Everybody, back.
巴里  诺拉  你看到他了吗
Barry? Nora, do you see him?
我...
I, uh...
I...
我看到他了  他还在这里
I see him. He's still here.
我们活在一个满是超能手机
We live in a world full of meta-phones
和超能风向标的世界
and meta-weathervanes.
接下来呢  我的电动牙刷吗
What's next? My electric toothbrush?
要等我们搞清楚怎样移除那些碎片
Till we figure out how to remove those shards,
-宁求稳妥以免后悔  -是的
- better safe than sorry. - Yeah.
既然马登和她女儿
Well, now that Mardon and his daughter
都被关进了铁山监狱
are all tucked away in Iron Heights.
你说我们和自己的家人团聚一下怎么样
What do you say we spend some time with our own family?
今年就我们和诺拉
Well, might just be us and Nora this year.
凯特琳和西斯科要翘掉感恩节了
Caitlin and Cisco are skipping Thanksgiving.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
-别问了  -什么
- Don't even ask. - What?
敬...
A toast to...
忘恩之辈
The thankless.
-敬忘恩之辈  -敬忘恩之辈
- The thankless! - The thankless!
敬忘恩之辈
The thankless!
来吧
Allez-oop.
好了  小子们   我来了
All right, boys, I'm tapping in.
好吧  我直说了
Okay, let me get this straight.
你们两个失败者坐在这里
You two losers are sitting here
在我只能认为是星际飞船的酒吧里
in what I can only assume is the cantina of a starship,
酗酒和吃劣质食物
drinking and eating terrible food
但你们本可以和真正在乎你们的人一起
when you could be drinking and eating amazing food
喝酒和享用美食
with people who actually care about you.
好吧  好吧  听着
All right, all right, look.
你要是那么想...
When you put it like that...
-她说的有道理  -你说的有道理
- She has a good point. - You have a good point, yeah.
顺便说一下  今年我没什么好庆祝的
And, by the way, I have the least to celebrate this year
因为我大部分时间都毫无意识
because I spent most of it unconscious.
你们几个呆子还要不要过感恩节了
You nerds come to Thanksgiving, or what?
与其说是尝  不如说是嚼
So it wasn't so much the taste as it was the crunch.
等等  你是在说...
Wait, are you actually saying--
是的  就在那年我发现
Yes, that was the year I found out
埃丝特祖母的地瓜泥为什么那么好吃
why Grandma Esther's yams tasted so good,
因为她从来不清洗她最喜欢的煎锅
because she never cleaned her favorite skillet.
我想也是在那一年
I take it this was also the year
你不再吃埃丝特祖母的地瓜泥了吗
you stopped eating Grandma Esther's yams?
我可没那么说
Uh-uh, I didn't say all that.
请允许我来敬酒
Allow me to propose a toast.
首先敬干净的餐具
Well, first to clean dishware,
然后敬家人
and also to--to family, all right,
然后敬朋友  新老朋友们
and to friends, old and new.
还敬征服这片土地的殖民者...
And to the colonizers who conquered this land...
-什么  -还有...
- What? - And...
-那些殖民者掠夺了...  -记得...
-the colonizers who grabbed-- - Remember-- no...
他们只拿走他们想要的东西
What they want, they just take what they want.
-我知道  但是我们的...  -敬拿走你的...
- Yes, I know, but our-- - To taking what you--
这不是...  不如这样  我们走吧
That's not--you know what? Let's go.
-现在吗  -好吧  你知道吗
- Right now. - Okay, you know what?
我觉得是时候去切火鸡了
I think that it's time to go carve a turkey.
太好啦
Great.
诺拉
Nora.
从机场开始我们就没机会聊下
Um, we didn't have a chance to talk since the airport.
爸  我知道你要说什么
Oh, Dad, I know what you're gonna say,
不用了
and you don't have to.
我看到你因为我
I saw what it was like
救那些人时迟疑的样子
when you hesitated to save those people
我感觉
because of me, and I felt...
-很糟  -是的
- Horrible? - Yeah.
我再也不想有这样的感觉了
And I never want to feel like that again.
我明白
I get it.
有时你必须牺牲自己去拯救别人
Sometimes you have to sacrifice yourself to save others.
即使这意味着抛下家人
Even if it means leaving your family behind.
不全是
Not exactly.
当我冲进暴风雨里
Look, when I ran into that storm I was thinking
我想的是  我想救所有人  但
I want to save everyone, but...
我一直最想的那个人是你
the person I was thinking about the most was you.
-我  -是的
- Me? - Yeah.
我不是选择放弃家人做闪电侠
I don't choose being The Flash over being with my family.
我是为了家人而做闪电侠
I'm The Flash for my family,
我不用跑去未来
and I don't have to run to the future
理解我为什么牺牲自己
to understand why I sacrificed myself.
我会为了救你  你妈妈
I'd do it to save, and your mom,
还有所有我爱的人而牺牲自己
all the people I love.
可能有一天如果我有足够的训练
You know, maybe one day if I train enough,
我能够救你
I'll be able to save you.
我从未怀疑
I don't doubt it.
-好啦  走  -好
- All right, come on. - Okay.
-太棒了  -好的
- Ah, yes. - All right.
-谢谢上帝  -切火鸡
- Hey, thank, God. - Carve the turkey.
-好  宝贝  -开始吧
- Yeah, baby. - Here we are.
-每个人都有一只火鸡  -不
- Each person gets a turkey. - No.
我们一起吃一只
We have the one for everyone.
-你还好吧  -就爸爸拿刀
- You all right? - Just Dad with a knife,
有点  是最好玩的部分
It's a little-- - It's the most fun part.
你很擅长
Oh, you're very good at that.
是吗
Am I?
奥林
Orlin.
我告诉你了这太危险
I told you it's too risky.
中城警局已经在找你了  你在这做什么
CCPD's already looking for you. What are you doing here?
是感恩节  医生  我来和家人一起过
It's Thanksgiving, Doc. I'm here to be with my family.
我希望你乐观点
I want you to be optimistic,
但我不会骗你的
but I'm not gonna lie to you.
至于还要多久
As far as how long,
鉴于她所遭受的脑出血
with all the brain hemorrhaging she suffered,
你得做好准备
you have to prepare yourself for the possibility
她可能醒不过来了
that she may never wake.
这都是我的错
This is all my fault.
不  是因为超能力者
No, it's these metas.
未加抑制的浩劫
Wreacking havoc unchecked.
她不该承受这些  德怀尔先生
She didn't deserve this, Mr. Dwyer,
你也一样
and neither did you.
这是周二那晚的场景  再次
This was the scene Tuesday night as, once again,
闪电侠从毁灭中拯救了中城
The Flash saved Central City from certain destruction.
世界范围的停电致使
After a world-wide power outage
所有国家都处于黑暗之中
blanketed every country in darkness,
一种奇怪的紫色
a bizarre purple...
这种毁灭性的现象
The destructive phenomenon emanated
来自一个坠入
from a satellite that had fallen
衰退轨道的卫星
into a decaying orbit.
幸运的是  在这个卫星
Thankfully, before the satellite could
撞击城市  导致科学家
strike the city and create what scientists believe
认为的灾难性事件之前
would have been "A catastrophic event,"
闪电侠摧毁了它
The Flash was able to destroy it.
大悟之道余波
再次  我们伟大城市的居民
Once again, residents of our proud city,
可能还有整个世界
and perhaps the entire world owe The Flash
都要感谢闪电侠和他的同伴
and his allies...
新超能力者相关
一个新的超能力者最后一次被看到
A new meta was last seen jumping off a building
是在偷珠宝后为了躲避追捕从楼上跳下
in order to evade capture after stealing jewels...
据报道  他劫持了一辆装甲车
It was reported that he escaped Flash's grasp
逃脱了闪电侠的追捕
after hijacking an armored vehicle.
今天早些时候
新超能力者再次袭击
我得修正它  格蕾西
I'm gonna make this right, Gracie.
每个超能力者
Every meta...
都得死
will die.
各位  最好是个好理由
Guys, this better be good.
对  我们有个感恩节后的传统  睡觉
Yeah, we've got an after-Thanksgiving tradition called sleeping,
怎么了
so what's up?
很好  相信我们  侦探
It's good. Trust us. Detective.
我突然想到
Well, it occurred to me that if you,
如果你们  韦斯特艾伦先生和太太
monsieur and madam West-Allen,
想和家人一起过节
you want to spend this holiday with your family.
可能你的超能力者杀手也想如此
Well, perhaps your meta-killer does as well.
所以我让西斯科先生黑入了
So I had monsieur Cisco hack into the CCTV footage
医院的监控录像  这是我们拿到手的
of the hospital and this what we got.
自从格蕾丝到这
Ever since Grace arrived,
只有一个人来看过她
only one man has come to visit her.
每天
Every day.
包括今晚
Including tonight.
闪电侠小队  请看
Team Flash, I give you...
奥林·德怀尔  也被称为
Orlin Dwyer, also known as...
蝉
Cicada.